Finding Aid for Flora Burt Collection, ca. 1830s-1960s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Flora Burt Family Papers ca. 1830s-1960s
Burt, Flora, collector.
3 linear ft. and 1 oversize folder
9810 Aa 2 UAm
Family historian; collected materials relating to the Burt family and other related families.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Flora Burt (donor no. 6368 ) and came from the executor of her estate in 2004 and 2006.
The collection is open to research.
Flora Burt was the historian of her family and the collector of original documents and photographs from the various lines within her family tree.
Historical documents, family papers, and photographs accumulated and maintained by Flora Burt relating to the Burt family and to other family lines. Included are materials and information pertaining to James P. McKinstry, officer in the U.S. Navy in the 19th century, and to John R. Williams, 1st mayor of Detroit. The collection also contains letters, 1839-1846, to William A. Burt from his son Alvin Burt, then doing survey work in Iowa; also letter, 1845, from William Burt to Alvin Burt, describing the solar compass that he patented.
Subjects:
Burt family.; Burt, William Austin, 1792-1858.; Cole family.; Detroit (Mich.)--History.; Iowa--Surveys--History.; McKinstry, James P.; Solar compass.; Williams, John R., 1782-1854.; Williams family.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Belle Isle (Detroit, Mich.); Burt, Solon.; McKinstry, James P.; Waterworks Park (Detroit, Mich.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Contributors:
Burt, Alvin.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Cartes-de-visite.; Photographs.; Tintypes.
- Photographs
  - Portraits of various members of different families (Burt, McKinstry, Williams among others), ca. 1860-1900 (Box 1)
    (include albums, carte de visites, daguerreotypes)
    (also includes album of Civil War generals and officers)
  - Portraits, photos of family members, special occasions, and residences, ca. 1860s-1960s (Box 2)
    (albums, carte de visites and cabinet photographs)
- Family papers
  - Alvin Burt, letters to his father William A. Burt, 1839-1846 (Box 3)
  - Alvin Burt, letters to other family members, etc., 1841-1845 (Box 3)
  - William A. Burt, letter to his son Alvin Burt relating in part to solar compass, April 9, 1845 (Box 3)
  - John R. Williams estate (Box 3)
  - Radio program "River Town Sustaining" (Box 3)
    (re John R. Williams in part)
  - Williams family, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Williams-related litigation (Box 3)
  - Ferdinand Williams (Box 3)
  - Notes of Julien Williams regarding family affairs (Box 3)
  - Julien Williams estate (Box 3)
  - James P. McKinstry -- U.S. Navy papers, 1820s-1860s, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - James P. McKinstry naval appointments (Box 3)
    (with presidential signatures)
  - Mary W. McKinstry estate (Box 3)
  - McKinistry Burt estate (Box 3)
  - Heinrich A. Pickert (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Cole family genealogy and related correspondence (Box 3)
  - Genealogical miscellaneous (Box 3)